OLDER TED:
Back in 2009,
your Aunt Robin
got a job hosting
a morning show.
Which meant she had to get up
kind of early. How early?
Morning, everybody.
Hey!
MARSHALL:
Hey, Robin!
So you're actually doing it,
huh?
You're
actually going
to work at 2:00 a.m.
Okay, I'm not
doing it for me.
I'm doing it for the fans.
Who exactly are the fans
of a show that airs at
4:00 in the morning?
People getting
up to host a show
at 5:00 in the morning?
Ha, ha, ha.
Meth addicts who haven't
sold their TVs yet?
Strippers in
that messy gray area
between getting off work
and getting their
kids up for school?
Them's my peeps.
All right, catch me up.
What's been going on?
You know,
just the uzhe.
Really, the uzhe?
Yes.
Robin, think
of the funniest thing
that has ever happened.
Got it.
Now double that.
So, a chimpanzee
wearing two tuxedos?
(LAUGHS)
Something
even funnier than that
happened to Marshall today.
Okay,
first of all, there's
nothing funnier than that.
Second of all, look,
it's not that good
a story.
Oh, come on, you guys.
You're four young,
active people living
in the
most exciting
city on Earth.
You're telling me you
have no stories for me?
What can I say? Some
weeks are just like that.
It's the
same thing
over and over.
A kid
in my class
ate some paste.
I used deceitful
means to hook up with
a less-than-intelligent girl.
My ex-girlfriend,
Karen, moved to town.
It's just...
It's all the
same, Robin.
Karen's in town?
You have got
to be kidding me!
No!
OLDER TED: Kids, I think
I've told you about Karen.
She was
my girlfriend
in high school
and
intermittently
during college.
She was beautiful, smart.
I was madly in love with
her.
The only problem was,
Marshall and Lily
were not.
I think it had something to
do with every time Karen
opened her mouth.
I love that you
guys live in a dorm.
It's so American.
It's like,
"Let's all eat baloney
sandwiches and be racist."
Oh, my God, she
was such a douche.
Dude, she was the heiress
to the Massengill fortune.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
She really wasn't that bad.
Of course,
you think that.
She turned you into
one of her douche
zombies.
"I want to
eat your brain, but only if
it's organic and grass-fed."
What?
Will you pass the salt?
Salt?
So bourgeois.
Totally.
What's that thing?
That's a TV, Karen.
Oh.
I don't watch TV.
Totally.
You thought
I actually bought
tickets to WrestleMania?
I was being ironic.
Totally.
I know that you
were being ironic.
I, too, am being ironic.
Let's do this!
What?
That makeup didn't
come off for a month.
I had to meet
Lily's parents that way.
I've never looked
like a bigger jackass.
Until today.
Tell the story.
Just let it go!
Well, hold on.
Is it really funny?
Robin,
I am not kidding you.
I almost don't
want you to hear it,
because seriously,
for the rest of
your life,
nothing else
will ever be as funny,
and you will curse yourself
for agreeing
to ever hear it
in the first place.
But seriously,
you got to hear it.
It's so funny.
(SIGHS) Fine.
MARSHALL: I was
at the company gym this
morning playing basketball.
Now, the guys I work with
can be pretty brutal
with their ridicule.
Hey, look at Wisniewski.
He's gonna cry. Look at him.
(LAUGHING)
Yeah, look at him.
I don't know.
I don't think knees are
supposed to bend that way.
I think he might
have torn his ACL.
Bro, the only thing that guy
tore was his cervix or
maybe his hymen.
Yeah, or his Fallopian tubes.
Boom!
(BOTH LAUGHING)
I may
have cleaned up
the dialog a little bit.
Anyways,
I go to my duffle bag
to get out my work clothes...
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
I want to say it.
Fine. You say it.
Marshall goes to his
duffle bag to get out
his work clothes and...
No, no, no, you say it.
It's funnier if you say it.
No, let me say it.
No, no, you say it.
You say it. Say it.
Same time.
No, no, no, you go.
You go.
I forgot...
Marshall forgot his pants!
(LAUGHING)
He forgot his pants.
Okay, Marshall
forgot his pants.
That's pretty funny.
It's no chimpanzee
wearing two tuxedos.
(LAUGHING) I mean,
what did he...
He forgot he put
the first one on?
Stupid monkey.
So Karen
in New York.
Weird, right?
Ted,
you cannot get back
together with Karen.
I never said
I was going to get
back together with her.
But
I was thinking,
she's new in town.
Would it be the worst thing
in the world if I gave her
a call?
No, no, Ted, it wouldn't be
the worst thing in the world.
It would be
the fourth worst thing.
Number one, super volcano.
Number two,
an asteroid
hits the Earth.
Number three,
all footage of
Evel Knievel is lost.
Number four,
Ted calls Karen.
Number five, Lily
gets eaten by a shark.
I'm Lily and I approve
the order of that list.
You don't know
the whole story.
Ted and Karen were
off-and-on all through
college,
and it always
went the same way.
They'd be having fun,
douching it up, and
then one day...
I know you think
pepperoni is fascist,
and
you're totally
right, so I...
Oh, my God! Karen!
(SNIFFS)
Sorry, bro.
Before you say anything,
I think that
you should read
Baudelaire's
Les Fleurs du Mal.
Okay.
So then they break up.
Ted would be all
depressed and we would wait
the appropriate amount of time
and then
we would tell him
how we really felt.
Karen and I broke up.
We hated her!
Bitch had to go!
And then Ted would
build up a head of
steam
and finally take the bus to
Providence to give Karen
a piece of his mind.
How'd it go?
Great.
Look who's back!
Karen!
And then, sure enough,
the whole thing would
start all over again.
Make that 10,002 Maniacs,
because I got us Natalie
Merchant...
(SNIFFS)
Sorry, bro.
So she would come visit you
at school and the second
you turned your back,
she would bring guys
back to your dorm room?
Respect.
Okay, I was an idiot.
She was
my first real girlfriend.
I was madly in love with her.
We all did stuff
we regret in college.
Junior year, Marshall grew
a soul patch, wore a Rasta
hat,
and asked everyone to
call him M.J. Smooth.
I don't regret
that for one second.
So you guys absolutely
don't think I should
call her?
ROBIN: Ted, no!
Of course not!
Get it through
your thick skull!
Okay, okay, fine, I won't.
Interesting piece of trivia,
I called her.
What are you doing?
You idiot!
Finish the pants story.
I can't believe
you called her.
Why don't you just ask her
to lunch while you're at it?
Because, Lily, I'm not going
to ask her out to lunch,
again.
Wow.
You asked her to lunch?
Why would anyone want to
have lunch with their ex?
Glad you asked, Marshall.
There are four
possible motives
behind an ex lunch.
Number one, they want
to get back together.
Oh. Like my high
school boyfriend,
Scooter.
Lilies, clever.
I'm sorry
I don't have
a scooter for you.
(LAUGHS)
My God, that's funny!
I forgot how funny you are.
Where is that waiter?
Why? You like waiters?
I can be a waiter.
I'm going to be the greatest
waiter on this Earth, and
then you'll love me.
Number two,
they want to kill you.
Like when I had
lunch with Wendy.
I'm glad
we could finally do this.
You know,
after the ninth time
you rescheduled on me,
I almost gave up on you.
But you didn't.
You just kept on trying.
By the way, there's something
I've been meaning to give you.
Gun! She's got a gun!
(STAMMERING) It's a tie.
Number three,
they actually do want
to give you your stuff back.
Like when I had
lunch with Curt.
By the way, there's something
I've been meaning to give you.
(GASPS)
My snub-nose
.38 Police Special!
God, I knew
I left that
somewhere.
Every time I watch
the news, I'm like,
"Oops.
Hope that wasn't my gun."
(CHUCKLES)
Breaking up was
the right choice.
Or number four,
to rub your face in
how great they're doing.
Like
my lunch with
Nicole Barsamian.
Who's Nicole Barsamian?
My ex.
Hello, Nicole.
You look well, Marshall.
You look okay, I guess.
I'm seeing someone.
Already? Who?
Lee Roberts. He reads
at a fifth-grade level.
You have to
cancel the lunch.
I would definitely do that,
definitely, except I
already had it.
Robin, I'm going to need to
borrow the butt of your gun.
I actually
lost it again.
Can you believe that?
How could you break
bread with that woman?
It was just lunch, and you
know she doesn't eat wheat.
We had a great
time catching up.
I mean, we even laughed about
what jerks we were back then.
(LAUGHING)
I can't believe
I had a beret for
each day of the week.
I can't believe
I had an iron-on image
of Moliere on my backpack.
Man, we were pretentious.
So pretentious.
What can I get you?
Hi.
(CLEARS THROAT)
I don't want
to cause a scene,
but
your wine list has
a Chateauneuf-du-Pape
listed under your
Cotes de Provence.
You might want to
alert your sommelier.
And for you?
I hate to go off-menu, but can
we have some bruschett with
fresh mozzarell?
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
It was great.
I mean,
there was one weird
moment towards the end.
Yeah, I mean, how do
you say goodbye in
those situations?
A kiss
on the cheek
is too familiar.
A handshake
is too formal.
And a hug is just
like a public dry
hump.
I think
you're hugging wrong.
So what happened?
Well...
Schopenhauer made a saucy
little argument in which
he posited...
Ted, honey, I want you to go
outside and bite the curb.
I'll be out in a minute.
Hey,
Karen was the first
girl I ever loved. Okay?
And after the year I've
had, I... I don't know,
I guess having lunch with her
just reminded me of what it
was like to be 18
and have my whole
life figured out.
And I would like to
remind everyone that
at least I was
wearing pants,
Marshall.
No! No, no, no!
You can't
just go changing
the subject like that.
Oh. Yeah,
the pants story.
Pants story, bomaye!
There's no story!
I had a little situation,
so I called Lily.
And just refresh us,
what was that situation?
I forgot my pants.
(GIGGLING)
What do you mean
you forgot your
pants?
I forgot them.
Now,
I need you to
bring me some.
What about your spare pants?
Last Thursday,
the mustard incident?
Jeez, woman, you have
the memory of a goldfish.
No, Ted, you're not
getting off that easy.
Marshall's pants story,
while amusing...
Amusing?
Try very amusing.
...is nothing compared
to this Karen madness.
Finish your story.
What?
That's it. It was just
one kiss in the restaurant.
Why did you say
"in the restaurant"?
Did you kiss
somewhere else?
Like where, in a tree?
No,
Lily, we did not
make out in a tree.
What's with this one?
Oh, Ted.
What did you do?
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
Ted, how could you?
Ted, Marshall forgot to
bring his pants to work
today,
and you're
still the stupidest
person at this table.
Okay, Lily,
let's be honest.
We both know your
real motivation here.
You hate Karen
because she lingered.
You son of a bitch.
What do you mean
she lingered?
February 5th, 1998.
I was painting...
Sorry.
I... Sorry. I...
You know, that color palette
is a bit derivative of early
Van Gogh,
don't you think?
Cheat on Ted,
criticize my
painting,
whatever,
that's your business.
But I catch you
peeping on my man's
junk and you linger?
You gots to get got.
The game is the game.
In Karen's defense,
I had just worked out.
Why'd
you have to paint
Marshall nude anyway?
Because he ate
my bowl of fruit.
Look, the point is,
Karen is a dirty
lingerer,
and you
cannot bring her
back into our lives.
Relax,
it was just
that one night!
And the next
three after that.
And one morning.
(LILY EXCLAIMS)
(CHUCKLING) But at least
I had pants on, Marshall.
Although, actually, I didn't.
Wait,
this happened
in our apartment?
Mmm-hmm.
Where was I?
You know those sleeping pills
you're taking to keep on your
crazy new schedule?
I think
they're stronger
than you realize.
LaFontaine gets
the puck to Turgeon.
Turgeon shoots. Glove save.
Hey, Ted. Hey, Lily.
Don't worry.
I won't tell
Marshall.
I'm gonna grab a beer.
You want one?
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Beer! I'll start
decanting the
Bordeaux.
(MOANING)
Ted, sure it's fun
to look back at a time
when you were
a fresh-faced farm
girl with a virgin's glow.
But all that stuff,
Ohio, Karen, college...
All that was BS.
"Before Stinson."
Now your life is awesome!
I mean, yeah, you still live
with your ex-girlfriend,
which is ridiculous.
Your Laser Tag chops
are almost nonexistent.
And your wardrobe, it's like,
what, are you allergic to
quality fabrics?
Seriously,
Ted, shape up.
What were we talking about?
So what's next
with this broad?
Oh, please,
the story's
already written.
Ted is Charlie Brown trying to
kick the football and Karen's
Lucy,
who pulls it away
at the last second
and has sex with it.
ALL: Ew!
You guys know what I mean.
Ted's gonna fall in love,
and then Karen's
gonna cheat on him
with some meathead,
who's like,
(SNIFFS)
"Sorry, bro."
(LAUGHS)
Wrong, wrong, wrong!
You must have
left the right answer
in your pants, Marshall,
because
that's exactly
what didn't happen.
OLDER TED: Because
here's what happened.
One afternoon, we
were at Karen's
place...
Karen? Oh, my God.
How could you?
(SNIFFS)
Sorry, bro.
OLDER TED: So, this time,
the meathead Karen was
cheating with...
Was me, Ted. Me...
Remember that time
Marshall forgot
his pants?
Damn it, Ted!
You quit trying to
change the subject.
You crossed the line.
You are complicit in
breaking some poor
guy's heart.
And you, you of all people
know exactly how that feels.
You really
don't want to tell
the pants story, do you?
What?
Pants, pants, pants, pants...
Fine! Okay?
So,
Lily came down to the
office to bring me my pants.
And why did she
have to do that?
Because I forgot my pants.
(GIGGLING)
Lily,
what are you doing here?
I'm here to give
Marshall something.
Ah.
Here to give
him something.
Got you. Nice.
Yeah, but I'm in a hurry.
Can I just give it to you?
Sure, okay.
And then you'll
give it to him?
Wait, hey.
I don't know
about all that.
I mean, yours would
have to be really good.
What are you talking about?
Marshall forgot his pants,
so I'm bringing him a new
pair.
Huh.
Marshall forgot his pants.
Well, it's a good
thing that you came by
because he has a really
important meeting today,
and it would be
pretty embarrassing
and not at all funny
if he were to show
up not wearing pants.
So, I'll make sure
he gets these.
Great. Thanks, Barney.
And you didn't
give him his pants.
Theodore Evelyn Mosby.
Of course
I gave him his pants.
I gave
Lily my word.
My word is oak.
Though I did make
some alterations.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Now,
as you'll see on
page 44 of the contract...
Hey, Eriksen,
when did you
join AC/DC?
(ALL LAUGHING)
Ha, ha, ha, ha.
Now,
can we please just turn
to page 44 of the contract?
Hey, Eriksen,
I think the   Oliver Twist
auditions are down the hall!
Hey, Eriksen, "Please, sir,
may I have some more pants?"
More pants!
Oh, my God!
That's it?
That's the whole story?
So what happened with Karen?
I'll finish it for you.
Ted left without
saying anything and Karen
got exactly what she wanted.
Mmm-mmm.
Not this time.
So, you have a boyfriend?
We've been drifting
apart for a long time.
I've been meaning
to break up with him.
God, Karen,
you are unbelievable.
You don't have the guts to
break up with someone like
a decent human being,
so instead you
pull this crap.
Okay, you're right.
I'm great with books.
I'm great with art.
I'm great with identifying
French wines from within
a mile
of where the
grapes are grown.
But I'm really
bad when it comes to
looking someone in the eye
and telling them the
truth about how I feel.
Well, we're both bad at that.
But I think we
both need to change.
So why don't I go first?
Karen, you're a really
hurtful and reckless
person,
and I never
want to see you or
speak to you again.
Au revoir.
Ted, wait.
Actually,   "au revoir"  means
"until we see each other
again."
So, I'm assuming
that you mean we will
in fact see each other again?
(SNIFFS)
Sorry, bro.
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
Thank you. Thank you.
Yes!
Bravo.
Ted, I am impressed with you.
You, too, Marshall.
Have you been
wearing those
all day?
They show off my calves.
Pants story.
Tell it again.
You know,
maybe it was good
you called Karen.
It definitely was. And not
just for me, but for her, too.
Later that night,
she sat down with Jerry,
and she had
the break-up talk she
always avoided with me.
OLDER TED:
So you see, kids,
sometimes when
you have to have
a tough conversation,
the best thing to do...
Wait a second.
You said you
were never gonna talk
to Karen again, right?
Yeah.
Then how do you know
she took your advice?
Hmm?
Oh! Right.
Well, about that.
After she
broke up with that dude,
she called me, we went out,
we hooked up,
and we've been
dating ever since.
We're really seeing
eye-to-eye, and this time,
I don't know, it just
feels different somehow.
Here she comes now.
Be cool! Hey!
ALL: (MUMBLING) Karen.